Portfolio GitHub LinkedIn

82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@alienresident.net • 347 228 3696

# Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over fifteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

### **UX/UI Skills**

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas
- · Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping
- · Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS)
- · Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles
- Typography and Graphic Production

## **Technical Skills**

- Sketch, Photoshop, OmniGraffle, Illustrator, Flash
- HTML, CSS, Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery
- · SVN & Git, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

# **Professional Experience**

## Spies & Assassins | kbs+

March 2015-present

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Spies & Assassins | Kirshenbaum Bond Senecal & Partners

- Create wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the redesign of the My BMW website
- Create wireframes and user flows for the 360° interactive Tour of Tomorrow showcasing the innovations of new BMW 7 Series
- Create mockups for the interactive informational signage for Bank of Montreal at Toronto's Billy Bishop Airport

## **New York University**

October 2008-March 2015

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- · Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's *Email Direct* a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011–August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u> a
  digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media
  studies

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Design and develop <u>MediaCommons</u> a digital network for professors and post-graduate students — using Drupal
- Establish a distinctive look and feel for the *MediaCommons* network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

## Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

#### Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

- Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

#### **Web Designer and Developer**

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive e-seminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

## Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### **Web Designer**

e-Scholastic

- · Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive quizzes and educational activities

## Thirteen, WNET

February 1998-December 1999

#### **Production Artist and Animator**

Heritage Project DVD-ROM

• Produce over 500 interactive maps for an DVD-ROM historical atlas feature of the award winning Jewish history television series, *The Heritage Project* 

## Education

1999–2007 Ph.D. Media & Communication, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995-1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991–1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

# **Additional Information**

## **Teaching**

**The New School**, Fall 2004–Spring 2008 Adjunct faculty member, *Media Studies* 

• Courses: Foundations of Media Design and Digital Video Effects

**Columbia University**, Summer 2005–Summer 2008 Instructor, *High School Program* 

· Course: Digital Filmmaking

## Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup Type Directors Club

# Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

#### **Presentations**

- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- Rapid Protoyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUI 2014 30th September, 2014

## **Event Organization**

- **DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10** Co-Organizer & Designer *NYC Drupal Users Group* June & December 2011
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014

## **Trainings**

- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015